Speaker 1: Yeah, you should come on a
Speaker 2: little front.
Speaker 3: Great.
Speaker 4: Hi! We all are the same height, I think. We are? 5'7 and a half. Are you for me? I'm 5'3. You're 5'3? I'm 5'3. I'm just a half.
Speaker 5: Oh, I feel like you're 5'7. People tell me I feel like I'm just 5. 5'1. You guys come up in the front. Yeah, of course. Come
Speaker 7: on in. Yeah.
Speaker 7: No problem, no problem. Yes! We're all friends today. Yes. We're all here for the same call. That's
Speaker 8: right. Let's
Speaker 7: get this thing passed. Gotta check and make sure
Speaker 10: it's right side up. That's always my mistake.
Speaker 12: We're having
a team.
- Are
Speaker 12: you covering
Speaker 13: a big time, they're gonna see you. - No,
Speaker 12: please. - I'm
all
Speaker 14: about it. - Oh, you know what you're getting? I'm all about it.
- Awww. - Yeah, you want to go look one? - It's pretty too important to me.
Speaker 15: Oh, yes, look at you.
Speaker 16: Come with me, come with me. Good, good, good. Very in front of me. Yeah, you got it. Perfect. -
Thank you so much. - Before you say it's okay, man. It's pretty amazing. - I don't think
Speaker 17: any of these things are going to be part of this time.
I think
Speaker 19: part
Speaker 17: of this time we've done a single mistake. I just want to try to do it. They're
going to do it with it.
It's not
Speaker 20: going to be a cut on what it was, a million dollars, because it was a million dollars.
Dan, I think
Speaker 21: that's good.
I see if I have no idea what you're saying. Oh, yeah. We're going to be running off. We're going to be running off. I think we're going to be running off. We're going to be running off. We're going to be running off. We're going to be running off.
Speaker 22: We're going to be running off. We're going to be running
off.
Speaker 23: We're going to be running off.
We're going to be running off.
Speaker 25: Housing is a
Speaker 26: human
Speaker 27 (higher-pitched voice): right,
fight, fight, fight.
Speaker 27 (higher-pitched voice): Housing is
Speaker 28: a human
Speaker 29: right!
Speaker 30: FIGHT,
FIGHT, FIGHT, FIGHT!
Speaker 33: Housing
Speaker 31 (higher-pitched voice): is a human
Speaker 34: right,
fight, fight, fight!
Speaker 34: to fight. Housing is a
human right. What do
Speaker 35: we want?
Speaker 37: Housing.
When do we want it? Now. What do we want?
Speaker 36: Housing. When
do we want it? Now. What do we want? Social housing. When do we want it? Now. What do we
Speaker 38: want?
Speaker 39: Social
housing. When do we want it?
Speaker 39: Now. If we don't get it,
we should have
Speaker 39: We
don't get it, we shut it down! Make some noise,
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): y'all! Si se puede,
si se puede, si se puede, si se puede, si se puede!
Speaker 45: Si se puede, si se puede, si se puede, si se puede, si
Speaker 46: se puede,
Speaker 47: si se puede, si se puede, si se puede, si se puede, si se puede.
Speaker 41: Yes we can do
Speaker 48: something,
yes we can do something.
Speaker 48: Yes, we can do
Speaker 49: something, yes, we can do something.
Speaker 51: This is what
Speaker 53: democracy looks
Speaker 54: like. Show me what democracy looks like.
Speaker 54: Show me what
Speaker 56: democracy looks like! All the
Speaker 58: rent! All the rent!
Speaker 59: All the rent is tuned and high! All the
rent! All the rents! All the rents tuned!
Speaker 60: is
too damn high
Speaker 61: because the green
is, because the green is, all the red is too damn high. All the red, all the red, all the red, all the red is too damn high. All the red, all the red, all the red, all the red is too damn high.
Speaker 68: Let's do it in Spanish. - In Spanish? - Yes! - Of course.
- Yes, of course!
Speaker 5: - Okay, do you start? - Yes,
Speaker 69: I start. - You start, I follow you. - No, no, no. Don't be shy, we're trying to
Speaker 72: pass a
Speaker 73: lot here.
Speaker 69: Let's go!
Speaker 1: ¡Vivienda social para todos!
¡Vivienda social para todos! ¿Cuándo? ¡Ahora! ¿Qué queremos? ¡Vivienda social para
Speaker 74: todos!
Speaker 74: - When?
- When? -
Speaker 75: Five, five, five!
Housing is a human right! Five, five, five! Housing is a human right! Five, five, five!
Speaker 76: Housing is a human right!
Well, I guess
Speaker 78: we're done here. Hey,
Speaker 81: hey, ho, ho!
Speaker 84: Landlord
Speaker 86: greed has got
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): to go!
Landlord
Speaker 43 (higher-pitched voice): Greedo's got to go, hey hey,
Speaker 89: ho ho, Landlord Greedo's got
to go, hey hey, ho ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go, hey hey, ho ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go, hey hey, ho
Speaker 90: ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go, hey hey, ho ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go, hey hey, ho ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go, hey hey, ho ho!
Speaker 92: Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord
Speaker 94: Greedo's got to go, hey hey,
ho! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to go! Landlord Greedo's got to
Thank you very much.
Speaker 96: So
we're
Woman 97: here today because everyone deserves a safe, comfortable, affordable place to live. And without this, nothing in your life works. Not your family, not your education, not your health care, not anything. And a home is more than just four walls and a roof over your head. It is a source of stability and security. It's a place that you can make your own and take pride in. A home gives you the freedom and the opportunity to build the life that you want.
Woman 97: But for many Americans this dream is out of reach. In more than 90% of U.S. counties minimum wage workers can't afford even a modest one-bedroom apartment. Working families in some communities in Minneapolis are bidding for homes against the world's biggest and wealthiest private financial firms and they're losing.
Every
Woman 97: day, Americans are trying to figure out how to afford their lives. And millions of our friends and neighbors have a hard time finding and affording a place to rent, let alone putting the money together for a down payment to buy a home of their own. So how did we get here? Well,
Woman 99: for decades, the United States has not invested enough in housing, in building housing. We have severely neglected public housing, and we have outsourced much of housing development to the private market.
And
Woman 97: because of restrictive local zoning laws and rising construction costs, we haven't built nearly enough. Housing supply collapsed in the 2008 foreclosure crisis, and private equity firms and other big corporate interests moved in, and they were focused on delivering returns for their investors, not on solving the housing shortage. In Minneapolis and around the country, in Minnesota and around the country, investors with deep pockets started snatching up starter homes with all cash offers.
Woman 97: And families are being outbid by mysterious buyers thousands of miles away. Big corporate landlords, they're raising rents and they're ignoring tenant calls to fix the leaks and take care of the pests. And
our
Woman 99: constituents are paying the price. And frankly, honestly, they cannot afford it anymore. There is something broken about our system when people who live in neighborhoods that they've lived in for years have to move away from friends and family and jobs because they can't find a place to live.
Woman 99: And when teachers and firefighters and other essential workers can't afford to live in the communities that
Woman 97: they serve, that is just wrong. So we have a severe housing crisis in this country, and the private market cannot meet this moment on its own. Congress must act.
So I am
Woman 97: grateful that Vice President Harris and Governor Walz have offered up detailed, comprehensive, serious plans to jumpstart home construction, to lower
Woman 99: housing costs and to go after big companies that are rigging the market against renters and homebuyers. Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez and I have seen the same challenge and we have a plan to meet it with the
Homes Act.
Our bill
Woman 99: lays out a new way to meet people's needs through social housing. Instead of treating real estate as a commodity in the speculative market, we would underwrite the construction of millions of new homes so that they can remain affordable for the long term. It's a public option to build homes either for rent or for home ownership so people can build equity. Our bill would establish a new development authority to finance and build millions of homes in big cities
and
Woman 99: small towns all over the country. Rent would be permanently affordable so as your income goes up or down you pay more or less but you don't have to move. Every home would be built to modern efficient standards which would lower utility bills and every home would be built to last by a high quality
union member.
Our bill
Speaker 100 (higher-pitched voice): is a new model that levels the playing field for ordinary people who dream of a stable,
Woman 99: delightful, affordable place to live. It's a new strategy, but it is a model that is working around the country, around the world, and it is rooted in the history and the traditions of the people in the regions that Alexandria and I represent. We know that housing looks a lot different in Bemidji, Minnesota than in the Bronx, and so a one-size-fits-all approach, it's not going to work.
Woman 99: That's why our bill would task local and tribal governments, housing authorities, non-profits, and community land trusts like the Rondo Community Land Trust in St. Paul and one-roof community housing in Duluth, whom you'll hear from shortly. It tasks these trusted local organizations to develop homes that will blend seamlessly into the community and meet the needs of the people who live there.
We
Woman 99: believe that housing is a human right, like food or health care. And a home, a shelter, is the oldest and most basic of human needs. The Homes Act will create a new option to make this right a reality for everyone. We cannot rely on the private market to do it alone. The Homes Act
Speaker 101: creates another way, a new way, to give millions of Americans a safe, dignified, affordable place to call home.
Woman 97: Now...
I'm so
Woman 97: excited and honored to welcome Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez to the podium. Congressman Ocasio-Cortez reached out to me several months ago and asked about collaborating on this project. It has been a fantastic experience to work with her and her incredible team. Thank you so much for your leadership and
Speaker 103 (higher-pitched voice): your great ideas and your good work. Please welcome Congresswoman
Ocasio-Cortez.
Speaker 104: Thank you. Thank you so, so much. And
can we give
Speaker 105: another round of applause to Senator Smith for her incredible leadership and work here? It's
really
Speaker 106 (higher-pitched voice): so exciting, and I can't say how much of a pleasure it's been to work with you and under your leadership and with your
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): office as well. It's just been so fantastic, and this is really the core of what it takes in order to get things done in Washington, to have not just bicameral support but support where
we can unite people
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): across regions, backgrounds and cultures and states in order to legislate for the best of the American people. So thank you. So good afternoon,
Speaker 108 (higher-pitched voice): everyone. How's everyone doing today? It's
a stunning day
Speaker 108 (higher-pitched voice): out here in Washington
Woman 109: and it's a perfect day to stand together and take action for housing as a human right.
Woman 109: Today we are here to introduce a game-changing piece of legislation, the Homes Act, and I'm thrilled to be joined by Senator Tina Smith in co-leading this legislation. And I also want to take a moment to give
Woman 110: a special shout out to all of the amazing folks who made the journey on buses this morning and planes, trains, and automobiles.
Woman 110: From the Bronx and Queens and Minnesota and every advocate in between. I'm just so incredibly
Woman 109: grateful because it is really your voices and your organizing and your effort building
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): power, people power from the ground up that actually can build momentum to make things like this possible. So thank you. I want everyone here
Speaker 111 (higher-pitched voice): to imagine a not too distant future.
Speaker 111 (higher-pitched voice): Where you are able to wake up in your new home.
One that
Speaker 111 (higher-pitched voice): is beautiful,
Speaker 112: affordable, and perfect for raising
Speaker 113 (higher-pitched voice): or supporting your family. In this vision, the energy that's powering your home isn't dirty.
And it's not
Woman 109: choking the air with pollutants or flaring up your kid's asthma. The water flowing from the taps is fresh and clean.
Woman 109: And you don't have to worry about lead paint on the walls.
The schools
Woman 109: in your community are excellent. And when you step outside, you find a vibrant playground where children are already
Woman 110: laughing and playing.
Your kids
Woman 110: join them, forging connections and growing up in a strong, supportive community.
And just
Woman 110: around the corner
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): from that home,
A
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): community center is buzzing with activities where seniors are gardening or bird-watching, the community is learning to cook together and just celebrating the richness
of life.
Woman 109: This thing isn't a distant dream, nor should
Woman 114: it be a luxury. This was the reality for so many families in America just a few
Speaker 115: decades ago.
I
Woman 114: know that my parents, like many others, worked their entire lives to achieve a
Speaker 111 (higher-pitched voice): modest and stable life. And decades ago, they were able to scrounge and save to buy a home. It's unbelievable. Just a couple decades ago, they were able to purchase a small apartment in Parkchester for $45,000.
It's
Woman 109: crazy, right?
But in
Woman 109: the years since, the housing market has grown increasingly speculative and it got a lot tougher for working families across the country to find a decent home. Wall Street started to see houses as slot machines and started gambling on one of the most foundational parts of life for the American people. And when Wall Street lost, like in 2008,
Woman 109: It was us, working people who had to pay the price, not the bankers who made the reckless bets in the first place. When I was in college and my dad passed from an unexpected cancer, my mom fought tooth and nail to keep our house. And by the time I graduated from college, we were on the edge of foreclosure. We had
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): to sell our home before it was taken from us.
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): leaving us at the mercy of investors and big banks who were just waiting for us to lose our foothold. I remember so clearly having, you know, being able to have a cup of tea or coffee at the table and watching bankers and investors roll up in cars taking pictures of our house
Speaker 116: before it was even taken, or before, while we were still living in it.
And
Woman 109: plenty of other Americans can tell you that if you are a young family or just starting out and wanting to buy a home without generational wealth or help, or if you want to feel like you can rent a new place without fear of being priced out in a year or two, it can feel nearly impossible. This is not the American dream that we were promised.
Woman 109: We are here today because that is the unfortunate reality for so many working
Speaker 117: Americans. And we are here today because another way is possible and we are here to make it
happen. In New York, the
Woman 114: average minimum wage worker would have to clock in 104 hours a week just to scrape by for a modest one bedroom apartment. 104 hours a week and what are they left with?
Woman 114: A mere 64 hours to sleep, pick up
Woman 109: prescriptions, get their kids to school, cook a meal, and maybe find a moment to rest
Speaker 108 (higher-pitched voice): under the roof they work so hard to keep. If time is money, we are getting robbed. This country is staring down a full-blown housing crisis. A
Woman 109: crisis where affordable housing is slipping further out of reach, where nonprofit
Speaker 106 (higher-pitched voice): housing is scarce, and where Wall Street and corporate America's greed is perpetuating our destruction.
Speaker 106 (higher-pitched voice): More than half of American renters are spending more than 30% of their income on rent, more than ever before in U.S. history. Meanwhile,
Woman 109: private equity and the 1% are vacuuming up our housing stock and squeezing out homeowners and renters alike. Nationwide, one-third of
Woman 114: all residential real estate purchases are carried out in all cash. All cash.
In
Woman 114: Manhattan, over 50% of all residential purchases are carried out in all cash.
Speaker 118: This simply isn't right.
Speaker 113 (higher-pitched voice): This is crazy. But let me be clear, we do not have to live like this. We
Woman 109: need to put homes back in the hands of the people and reclaim the home as a basic human right, not a commodity for profit first.
Woman 109: A home should be a sanctuary, a place of stability and security, not a source of endless stress. The Homes Act offers a real solution to the scale and severity of this crisis. This bill will transform housing in America by establishing a national housing development authority to acquire and develop real estate, creating and maintaining a stock of permanent,
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): affordable housing.
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): This bill recognizes that there is no one-size-fits-all solution to the housing crisis and it is aimed to uplift the diverse set of living, breathing communities that working Americans have been building for decades. From public housing in places like New York and Puerto
Woman 109: Rico, to rural housing cooperatives in the Midwest, to community land trusts and tenants unions in California, any home that's built for people
Woman 109: not profit will be able to benefit from this authority in its first decade the homes act will invest 300 billion dollars into our communities funding over 1 million new housing units over 850 000 of those units will be for low and extremely low income families this includes both single and multi-family housing with strong tenant protections
Woman 109: There has been a lot of
Speaker 108 (higher-pitched voice): talk about building new housing in this country, but too often we don't talk about who will be building that new housing.
Speaker 120: This bill
Speaker 108 (higher-pitched voice): is about building good union jobs just as much as it is about building affordable
Woman 110: homes.
Woman 110: Every year, this bill will put over 150,000 Americans to work in good union jobs every year to build affordable housing. From construction to
Woman 114: operation to maintenance, this bill will generate more than 400,000 good-paying jobs across industries every year.
And we know
Woman 114: this plan is possible because we have
Woman 109: done it before.
Woman 109: During the New Deal, President Franklin Delano Roosevelt created a development authority much like the one we are proposing today. Folks may not be familiar with this history, but in New York, FDR's visionary program is still all around us.
His
Woman 109: authority built the first public housing in this country, including
Woman 110: the Williamsburg Houses in Brooklyn, and it went on to inspire communities like Co-op City in the Bronx and
Woman 109: Elecchester in Queens that are still thriving today. So to our detractors, we say this plan is not only necessary, it is reasoned, it is rational, and it is right.
It
Speaker 107 (higher-pitched voice): is rooted in the American dream, in the fundamental idea that everyone deserves a place to call home. Thank you. Thank
Speaker 100 (higher-pitched voice): you. Next, I would like to welcome to the podium Noah Hobbs, who is policy director at One Roof Community Housing in Duluth. Welcome, Noah.
Thank
Speaker 121: you. Thank you, Senator Smith and Representative Ocasio-Cortez, for introducing this. Like Senator Smith said,
Speaker 122: I'm Noah Hobbs. I'm the policy director at One Roof Community Housing. We are a multifamily, single-family, affordable housing developer out of Duluth, Minnesota, which is a Rust Belt port town of about 86,000 people. But we do work that goes up to Grand Marais, Grand Rapids, Two Harbors, Proctor, and Cloquet. So the northeastern part of Minnesota is our service region. So outside of Duluth, it's not a lot of folks living there. And so.
Speaker 122: So we've done 350 community land trust homes and also about 220 resales, so we've helped about 600 families achieve the American dream through home ownership, and then we've also redeveloped and developed about 330 units of a multi-family affordable housing all across northeastern Minnesota, so folks that aren't ready for home ownership yet can still have an affordable place to call home. One thing that we see in greater Minnesota is the fact that a two-by-four costs the same, whether near Duluth, Grand Rapids, New York, Milwaukee, or Chicago.
Speaker 122: And we also have lower incomes in greater Minnesota and greater America, and so there's an even greater mismatch of what that cost of home is and the cost to build because that doesn't come down with the cost of goods. Also, municipalities, smaller municipalities in greater Minnesota, smaller counties don't have staff, city staff or county staff, that are dedicated or knowledgeable enough to pull off affordable housing projects or they're dealing with all the other issues that face their communities and they can't do this because they're staffs of two, four, six, or eight and they're unable to do this issue. financing is
Speaker 122: another huge issue in greater minnesota we don't have as many philanthropic uh you know funders foundations uh as more uh urban areas do um and financing is harder to come from we don't have as large financial institutions that are willing to provide the capital let alone take the risk so this would fill a huge need uh in that and so also the biggest thing is this is probably the first outside of 2007 with the housing market collapse and with the american rescue plan act the single investment in housing in the past 30 years and so one roof is incredibly excited I'm excited.
Speaker 122: to endorse
it and
Speaker 122: again, thanks to Senator Smith and Representative Ocasio-Cortez.
Speaker 123: Thank you. Thank you so much, Noah. That's great. Thank
you.
Speaker 100 (higher-pitched voice): Now please join me in welcoming
Woman 97: Makia Griffin, who is Executive Director of the Rondo Community Land Trust in St. Paul,
Minnesota.
Thank
Speaker 124: you, everyone, and thank you so much to Senator Smith and Representative Ocasio-Cortez. As stated,
Speaker 125 (higher-pitched voice): I am a proud daughter and byproduct of the Rondo community in St. Paul, Minnesota. The Rondo community in St. Paul, Minnesota is the largest black community in the state at one point.
Speaker 125 (higher-pitched voice): And it was devastated with the influx of infrastructure, Highway 94. And that was back in the 50s. And the community has still suffered through, even through that, still suffered through continued
Woman 126: disinvestment or investment in the community, which really sometime back in the 80s, 30 years ago, community members got together and said, We need to figure out how do we preserve affordable housing
in the
Woman 126: community and they landed on the community land trust as a sure model to be able to not only hold down the ability for home ownership over the long term but also community and culture. I always like to start by saying that I don't know how many of you know this but the community
Speaker 127: land trust movement itself was created through
the black
Speaker 127: experience through the
Speaker 128: civil rights movement.
Woman 126: When political violence
told the
Woman 126: Sherrards, we need to do something different. And taking and owning community land together and benefiting from its economic benefits above together, weathering the ups and downs in communities together is exactly what this bill will be able to continue to forward and make larger. That work that was so pivotal back in the 60s actually has propagated
Woman 126: community land trusts across this nation and internationally. I am so proud today to stand here not only representing the very tall, wide shoes and tall shoulders I have to stand on in my own community as a daughter of Rondo,
Woman 126: And while I do have the privilege of supporting affordable home ownership across a county in the city of St. Paul and Ramsey County in Minnesota, I do have that weight and responsibility of ensuring that my community, Rondo, also has what it needs.
Woman 126: I'd also like to state we were the first community land trust in the state of Minnesota. We were also the first community land trust in the state of Minnesota to apply the community land trust movement to commercial
Woman 129: uses.
This is all
Woman 129: about, right? This is all about how do we want to see our communities thrive and prosper. This is about
Woman 126: coming together and creating people power
Woman 126: this is about creating the communities that communities want to see and this bill is so important to be able to give choice and autonomy to communities whether they want to own a community land trust home whether they want to own a community land trust home that is on community land trusted land that's a that's a cooperative there's so many things that we can do to provide home ownership opportunities to provide safe and affordable rental opportunities and to be able to good people.
Woman 126: the time that they need in order to make themselves whole and get along their own economic continuum and if we are not invested in the people of today we have no hope for for our little ones that are coming up it's important it's so important that we take the profit
Woman 126: out of housing and make and ensure that it benefits
to
Speaker 124: everyone that needs to have a home. Thank you again for all the work that is being done today.
- Thank you
Speaker 103 (higher-pitched voice): very much. Next we have the incredible Congresswoman Ayanna Pressley from Massachusetts.
- Good afternoon
Speaker 131: everyone.
Good
Speaker 132: afternoon, family. And indeed, not only are we movement family, but we are one human family. And that's what brings us all to
Woman 133: this moment, because we recognize that we're all tied to one another.
I want to
Woman 133: begin by thanking my sister in service, Representative Ocasio-Cortez. Thank you for your indefatigable, visionary leadership.
and
Woman 133: housing justice and so on, so many other issues of consequence. And I would share those same compliments to Senator Smith. Thank you for both of them, for their leadership and for convening us today to introduce this critical and necessary legislation, the
Speaker 134: Homes Act. The Homes Act.
Everyone should
Speaker 135: have a home. not just shelter, not be warehoused,
Woman 133: a place of belonging, the HOMES Act. I want to express my gratitude also to Aisha Hernandez, Makiya Griffin, Noah Hobbs for being here today and sharing your stories as I've said so often. I look forward to a day where people do not have to weaponize their lived experiences in order to compel action from their government, but I'm grateful for those every time they do it.
Every
Woman 133: time I return home to my district, the Massachusetts 7th, in every room I'm in one issue comes up over and over again. Whether I'm in Roxbury or Cambridge, whether I'm in Chelsea or Randolph, and that issue is housing. Today, I'm thinking about the single parent, like the household I grew up in, working two minimum
wage jobs,
Woman 133: Sleeping in their car because rent has skyrocketed beyond their reach. I'm thinking about the veteran who served our country only to be left to battle their PTSD on the streets because they can't find a place to call home.
I'm thinking
Woman 136: of the elderly couple who lived in their community for decades pushed out by gentrification
Woman 133: and left to watch.
as
Woman 133: luxury condos are built over the homes they raise their children in. These stories are an indictment
Woman 136: of the nationwide failure to ensure that housing, a fundamental human right, is accessible to
all.
Speaker 137: The rent is just
too damn high.
Woman 136: But let me be clear.
Woman 136: This housing crisis is not a natural disaster. It is a man-made catastrophe. Born from decades of repeatedly prioritizing profits
Woman 133: over people. You know, very often, progressives in our righteous indignation are misunderstood or some people give us a bad rap for being too
Woman 136: bold, too urgent.
Woman 136: too aspirational, too ambitious. Well, I'm all right with being audacious enough to believe that housing is a human right
Woman 129: and everyone deserves a home. I will be on that side of
history.
Woman 136: The Homes Act is more than just legislation. It is a lifeline.
Woman 136: It's a visionary solution that recognizes housing is a public good, a simple truth. This bill would create more than 400,000 jobs, build and preserve 1.25 million housing units that are actually affordable. When a child has a stable home, they can focus on their education.
Woman 136: When parents are burdened by crushing rent, they can invest in their
Woman 129: family's future. When seniors age in place, they can remain vital members of the communities they help to build. Housing is a
public good. And
Woman 129: this bill is about more
Woman 136: than just bricks and mortar.
Woman 136: It's about righting the wrongs of racist housing policies that excluded communities of color for decades. We can create, I'm just audacious, ambitious, and aspirational enough to believe
Woman 129: that we can create a society where everyone is safe, has access to safe, stable, and affordable housing.
It's not
Woman 129: just a right, but a reality for all.
Woman 133: Another world is possible, and we are building it together.
Our
Speaker 138: last
Speaker 139: speaker
Woman 97: today is Ayesha Hernandez with the Coalition to Save Affordable Housing at Co-op City.
Good evening,
Speaker 140 (higher-pitched voice): everyone.
My
Speaker 140 (higher-pitched voice): name is Aisha Hernandez. I've been living in Co-op City for about eight years. I was,
sorry I got
Speaker 140 (higher-pitched voice): confused. Let me start again. Okay, good afternoon. My name is Aisha Hernandez Ahmed. I'm a resident and co-owner of my home in Co-op City for
the
Woman 141: last eight years. Before living in Co-op City, I was a renter paying $3,000 a month and $6,000 in utilities.
Woman 141: Co-operative housing gave me the pathway to home ownership and sustainable cost of living. Now I live in a two bedroom apartment with a monthly maintenance for about $1,400. It isn't always smooth in crop
city.
Woman 141: Yes. A few years ago, my neighbors and I got together and formed the coalition to save affordable housing to make sure that our housing stays affordable, that our management is serving in the best interest of co-owners and fight for any attempt of any corporate takeover of co-op city. We have done this because we're co-owners and we're not in the whims of corporate landlords.
Woman 141: Which is why I'm here today in support of Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and Senator Smith to support the Homes Act bill. We're in the midst of a national housing crisis and I want my fellow Americans from New York to California to enjoy the same access and safe, affordable housing that Corp has given me.
We
Woman 141: have a lot of work to do, and this bill, we must make sure that it takes it. So let's get it done.
Thank you
Speaker 142: so much.
Woman 97: Thank
you so much to
Woman 97: all of our speakers. And now we would be happy to take a
Speaker 143: few questions from the press if anybody has any questions.
Speaker 144: We're going to
Speaker 143: just take questions from the press for now, Joel. Thank you. Okay. Thank you.
Speaker 145: Okay. Great.
Speaker 146: Thanks, everyone. Thank you, everyone. Thank you, everyone.
"Fight!
Speaker 147 (higher-pitched voice): Fight! Fight! Possing is a human right!
Fight! Fight!
Speaker 147 (higher-pitched voice): Fight!" "Fight! Fight! Fight! Possing
is a human right!
Speaker 147 (higher-pitched voice): Fight! Possing
is a human right!"